Jeff Scholen

Atlanta



About

I am a recent graduate of the Iron Yard's 12 week full time Rails Engineering Bootcamp. My core competencies are Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 and other related technologies. I have experience with RSpec and Test Driven Development. Prior to this, I had been working in engineering related roles in the manufacturing industry.

Phone: (404) 295-6995

Email: jmscholen@gmail.com

Twitter: @jmscholen
Github: jmscholen

Work Experience Remington Medical Inc.

Engineering Project Manager 2012 - 2013

Managed the development of medical devices. Responsible for the direction to a small team of enigneers.

- Led a team of department stakeholders and engineers to receipt of clearance to market a medical device from the FDA.
- Led a team to prove the viablity of a new technology platform for assembly of hyperdermic needles.
- Successully reduced the cost of an existing product line by 30%.

CardioMEMS Inc.

Senior Quality Engineer

2010 - 2012

Managed the quality system requirements for class II and III medical devices.

- Technical lead engineer responsible for compliance across all departments for meeting FDA and ISO requirements
- Successfuly managed external audits for complaince to quality system compliance

Facet Technologies Inc

R&D Project Manager

2004 - 2007

Managed the development of OEM medical devices.

- Technical manager responsible leading teams to design and transfer medical devices to manufacturing.
- Recognized for assisting the Sales and Marketing group with acquiring an \$8 million contract
- Recognized for saving the company over \$100,000 for sourcing needs thru ebay.com

Lucent Technologies Inc

Mechnical Designer

2000 - 2003

Responsible for CAD design and modeling of next generation manufucaturing processes for the research and development group.

 Recognized for introducing a novel manufacturing process to supply fiber optics bundles into a larger nested cabling system.

Education The Iron Yard

Rails Engineering, Ruby on Rails

Southern Polytechnic State University

Mechanical Engineering Technology, Bachelor of Science

1994 - 1996

Skills

- Web Development
 - Ruby on Rails
 - Postgresql
 - RSpec
 - TDD
 - HTML
 - CSS
 - Javascript
- Interpersonal
 - Optimistic
 - Calm
 - Reasonable
 - Speaks Effectively

References

Please contact Sarah Ladato. - The Iron Yard

Additional references available upon request. -